good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to the icsa lombard general
insurance company limited's q3 and
nine-month sy-22 earnings conference
call
from the senior management we have with
us today mr bhargav das gupta md and ceo
of the company mr gopal balochandran cfo
and cro
mr sanchez mantri executive director
retail
and mr aloo ka garwal executive director
wholesale
please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involved risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the lesson only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes
should we need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then zero on
the touchstone phone
i now hand the conference over to mr
bhalgravdasgupta mdn ceo ica sage and
lombard general insurance limited
thank you and over to you
thank you
uh good evening to each one of you thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of isis lombard general insurance
company uh for q3 and nine months of fi
22.
uh i hope you and your colleagues and
family members are all safe and healthy
i will give you a brief overview of the
industry trends and developments that
we've witnessed in the last few months
post this rca for mr gopal bala children
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter and nine
months ended december 31
2022.
the data for q3 fi 22
indicates that the momentum in
economy activity has gained further
traction aided by expanding vaccination
coverage and release of pent-up demand
contact intensive indus services and
urban demand recruit on in improving
consumer optimism
amidst this the researchers of covet 19
infections by the omicron variant has
created some sense of uncertainty
especially for service industry
while this may have some impact on the
near-term growth given the ramp up in
the vaccination program
its overall impact on the economy is
expected to be lower than the first and
the second wave
moving to the gi industry the industry
during qc f52 delivered mixed
performance
segments such as motor insurance witness
continued headwinds due to heightened
competitive intensity cheap shortages in
the four-wheeler segment and weak
festival demand in the two-wheeler
segment
health insurance on the other hand
continue to show robust growth primarily
driven by group health while growth in
retail health has moderated since q2 of
this fiscal due to base effect
as far as commercial lines are concerned
segments such as fire marine and
engineering lines witness strong growth
in sync with the current market
environment
overall the industry registered a growth
of eleven point two percent in nine
months of fbi 22 and a growth of eight
percent in q3 of fi 22 as per
disclosures on the website of irdi
the combined ratio of the industry was
119.3 in h1 fi-22 as compared to 105.6
in h1 of 2021 based on available
information from public disclosures
excluding three companies
further the overall combined ratio of
private multi-line general insurance was
112.4 in h1 fi 20-22 as compared to
103.2 in h121 excluding one company
moving to business impact this quarter
as you know we have been making
investments to benefit from the
opportunity that the current environment
has to offer especially in the retail
health segment
these investments are
gradually steering growth for us thereby
enabling us to gain market share in our
preferred line of business
in that backdrop of the thousand uh
incremental head count to be added in
our retail health agency sales force
we have rolled out offers for 800 and
have successfully onboarded close to 400
of them during this quarter
as a result we are seeing month-to-month
improvement in growth and we expect the
growth through this channel to
accelerate in the next few quarters as
the soil source starts getting
productive
as indicated during our earlier calls
there was a base effect on the health
benefit segment for the first three
quarters of f5982
from the middle of the current quarter
the base effect started to fade as a
result of which health business from our
banker channels grew by 15 in december
of 2021.
going ahead we expect this channel to
continue to deliver robust growth
our one-stop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs i'll take care app
has surprised surpassed 1.1 million
downloads with successful submission of
over 95 000 claims and over 55 000
technically consultation requests
our objective is to get closer to our
customers by providing a unique digital
platform for continuous engagement to
help them take better care of their
health motor and other risks anytime
anywhere
as indicated in our previous earnings
calls in group health segment our
continuous
direct engagement with large corporates
enabled us to retain over 90 of our
customers at a higher price thereby
improving in in premium per life since
june 2021
the underlying environment suggests that
the consumers are willing to pay a
higher premium for better coverage and
adopt technology for better customer
service thus creating an opportunity for
us to grow in this segment
in motors we continue to come combat
challenges from the lack of motor tp
rate hike for over two consecutive years
heightened competitive intensity in the
motor od segment chip shortages in the
new private car sales etc
however our expectation is that these
are short-term challenges
when we
take a closer look on ground on the
private car side the consumer sentiment
remains strong
and during the quarter we have continued
to focus on growing our market share in
certain key profitable sub segments
as far as the commercial lines are
concerned we have seen strong growth and
believe we are in that environment now
where the growth will continue
in current times the major major trend
has been the significant increase in
online buying by consumers
at icc lombard we have been continuously
investing in this front our digital one
team is set up like a full stack ensure
tech firm consisting experts across
functions operating together like a
fully functional entity within the
overall organizational framework
business source through our website
increased by 20 and q3 fi 22.
within this our health business grew by
22.9 travel business grew by 156.9
and motor business grew by 11.9 percent
business sourced by this
team through strategic alliance partners
in the digital ecosystem grew by 70 in
q3 of f52 our digital one business is
fully empowered to
deepmind customer data and fine-tune
customer outreach efforts service
customers to claim systems that enable
real-time communication and thereby
optimize cost of acquisition we are
excited on the progress of this channel
and believe it is all set to drive
benefit and benefit from the longer term
opportunity the current environment is
offering us
overall our focus on sustainable market
leadership continued through the third
quarter as we prioritize underwriting
discipline portfolio optimization and
growing in segments that are favorable
and fall within our risk appetite
we remain on track and are focused on
growth levels such as rendering our
distribution engine aided by lower base
effect
realizing synergy rationalizing cost
while scaling up our preferred lines of
business servicing customers with
excellence digital advance environment
advancements that will enable us to
sustain the return on equity objective
over longer term
i will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter
thanks vader and uh good evening to each
one of you
i will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for q3 and nine months five twenty two
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the effect of the day merger in the
financials has been incorporated in the
form of opening networks as on april 1
2021.
further the financials for the current
year represent numbers of the merged
entity
and the comparative number of the
previous year in the financials
pertaining to standalone icc lumbar and
hence they are not comparable
gross direct premium income of the
company was at 133.11 billion rupees in
nine months at 522 as against rupees
105.25 billion in nine months fry 21.
the industry reported a double digit
growth of 11.2 percent on a lower base
for a similar period
our gdp growth was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments given that
our approach has always been growing
business sustainably
the fire segment gdpi was raised 22
billion in nine months fi 22 as again
should be 17.48 billion in nine months
fi 21.
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall gdp of our property and
casualty segment was replaced thirty
nine point three four billion in nine
months five twenty two as against thirty
point six one billion in nine months
five twenty one
on the retail side of the business gdp
of the motor segment was which is fifty
eight point one five billion nine months
five twenty
as against rupees 51.48 billion and nine
months at 21.
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network to increase
penetration in tile free entire four
cities
our agent including the point-of-sale
distribution increased to 81 969 as on
december 31 2021 up from 78 0035 as on
september 30 2021.
the advanced premium was rupees 34.59
billion as at 31st december 2021 as
against
36.86 billion
as at september 30 2021.
resultantly combined ratio was hundred
and eleven percent in nine months fi
twenty two as against ninety nine point
one percent in nine months fi twenty one
and hundred and fourteen point three
percent in h one f by twenty twenty two
combined ratio was hundred and four
point five percent in quarter three five
twenty two as against ninety seven point
nine percent in quarter three five
twenty one and hundred and five point
three percent in quarter to f by twenty
two our investment assets rose to rupee
374.54 billion at 31 december 2021 up
from rupees 371.95 billion at september
30 2021. our investment leveraged net of
borrowings for 4.23 times at december 31
2021 compared to 4.27 times at september
30 2021.
investment income was at rupees 22.95
billion in nine months fbi 22 as against
rupees 16.59 billion in nine months
on a quarterly basis investment income
was at risk 6.9 billion in quarter 3 fbi
22. as against rupees 5.68 billion in
quarter three up by 21.
our capital gains was at risk six point
zero one billion in nine months fi
twenty two as against rupees two point
nine two billion in nine months five
twenty one
capital gains in quarter three five
twenty two was at risk one point three
one billion as against rupees one point
zero eight billion in quarter three up
by twenty one
the expenses incurred of approximately
rupees 0.16 billion on account of the
day merger has been observed in the p l
during nine months fi 22. as indicated
in our previous earnings call during the
integration process
we were able to smoothly transition and
onboard our partners to seamlessly
operate with minimal disruption
our branch network as at december 31
2021 stood at 285
as against 431
as at september 30 2021.
apart from the immediate benefit this
transaction entails an opportunity to
unlock significant operational and
revenue synergies in times to come
we are on the right path on our roadmap
of realizing this energy benefits by the
second half of fiscal 2023.
our profit before tax was rupees 12.73
billion in nine months five twenty two
has again should be fifteen point zero
four billion nine months at five twenty
one whereas profit before tax was rupees
four point two one billion in quarter
three five twenty two has against four
point one eight billion in quarter three
last year
consequently profit of the tax
was rupees 9.59 billion in nine months
five 22 f against 11.27 billion in
quarter nine months five 21
whereas coffee doctor tax for this
quarter three stood at 3.18 billion
as compared to
3.14 billion and quarter three up by 21.
return on average equity was fifteen
point one percent in nine months fi
twenty two as against twenty two point
four percent in nine months five twenty
one the return on average equity for
quarter three five twenty two was
fourteen point six percent as against
seventeen point six percent in quarter
three or five twenty one
solvency ratio was at two point four
five times at december 31 2021
as against two point four nine times six
september thirty twenty twenty one it
continued to be higher than the minimum
regulator's requirement of 1.5 times
as i conclude i would like to reiterate
we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth sustainable value
creation and safeguarding interest of
policyholders
at all times
i would like to thank you all for
attending our earnings conference call
and we would be happy to take any
questions that you have thank you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and 1 on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue you may press star
and 2.
participants are requested to use
answers while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question queue
assembles
[Applause]
the first question is from the line of
swarner mukherjee from bnk securities
please go ahead
yeah thank you for the opportunity sir
so i have couple of questions uh first
on the motorcycle if you could throw
some light on the reason for the
underwriting
uh
for this business
is this because of any kind of change
after amalgamation rpx
or any other driver of the
the underlying challenges more in terms
of the
distribution aggression that we are
seeing on the ground it's not not to do
with the merger on the merger front
actually we are quite happy with the way
things are progressing
um except for as we had earlier uh said
except for three or four oem dealership
we've in you know we've actually got
a complete synergy in terms of
benefiting from that distribution
channel
we are also uh
you know seeing growth across most of
the uh agency and the other distribution
channels that we've uh
you know acquired through the uh uh
integration the real challenge on the
ground has been uh
you know we've always found that
whenever the growth slows down in the
market because of you know because of
various pressure right now we have
challenges the market because of chip
shortage for private car because of
online demand for two wheelers so
overall the industry is not growing as
fast as it is used to uh the motor
insurance industry and whenever the
substitutions happen we find that the
market as in our industry gets very
aggressive on sourcing
that's the real reason why uh the motor
book is underperforming if you look at
the largely that's from the cost side on
the
loss ratio side it's also because of the
fact that the claims frequency has now
gone back to normal
first two quarters we had some benefits
because of relatively you know slower uh
you know utilization or lower
utilization because of some lockdowns
you know across the country
that has that went away in q3 so the
lost issues have climbed back up to uh
what we believe is more
normal so those are the real reasons uh
that we are seeing so it's more
underlying industry issues and you know
within that our uh experience rather
than any
uh rather than the merger
okay so uh then if i uh look ahead on
the motor side uh basically you have
commented uh that you know you had clean
some green foods in certain segments
so what would be the trends now because
uh i think uh this kind of challenges
are continuing for quite some time
especially competitive intensity so are
you seeing situations improving and what
is what is the status in terms of you
know you had talked about price
increases also in second segment earlier
yeah what we have been saying that we
don't like we expect that to happen or
at least our experience tells us that
that should happen from next year we
don't expect anything this year as we've
been saying
uh there are two components on the price
increase one is a third-party price
increase that is more uh tariff and
regulatory driven
again we believe that the industry needs
a direct price increase but that is as i
said you know driven by the regulator we
can't uh we don't control that
but two years we've not seen a price
increase we are hopeful that this year
we'll see one uh on the only side is
where we have greater control as an
industry and
as i said i think the industry benefited
a bit from the first quarter uh because
of uh lower usage and uh that's a
benefit that uh people probably have
factored in in terms of the aggression
so
we've never we've not we've been saying
that we don't expect a price correction
this year but we are hoping that we
should see that uh you know from next
year onwards historically we've never
seen you know two to three years of uh
price aggression uh in these two years
we've seen two covet lockdowns that has
probably been the reason why this is
sustained for this longer period
uh from our perspective i believe we've
kind of
uh you know done most of the connections
that we wanted to
and on this base we are reasonably
confident that we'll start going from
the coming quarter onwards
okay that's that's very helpful sir uh
additionally on the channel
may i request to please reach on the
queue we have participants reading sure
sure i'll join back thank you thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants please
limit your questions to two per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the lineup
abhishek saraf from jefferies please
call it
thanks for the opportunity
um
and so i had question on with regard to
our retention so it appears that this
quarter we have had a higher retention
at around 76 percent versus what was
there in the previous two quarters of
this year around 66 60 and 68
so what explains this stance which
category have we seen higher retention
and is it driven by the insurer or we
are doing it on our own volition that's
the first question uh second i noticed
that our investment yield both on the
policyholder investments or shareholder
investments have actually come down
uh
quarter and quarter
while the yield curve or the rates have
generally been on an upward trajectory
so if you can just help me understand
what has happened there also it will be
very helpful thanks a lot
so
i'll ask to take the first one
to the mix of business
with regard to the second one uh in
terms of the investment yield
the aggregate yield could be driven a
little bit by the
mix of capital gains that we have
overall the book is earning roughly
about seven percent
and when interest rates go up our mark
to market benefit that we are sitting on
the bond book that goes away but equally
the uh new flow that we get into the uh
you know investment portfolio that earns
a higher letter now given the overall uh
mix of the new flow versus the old stock
the new flow impact is very little
because it takes some time for you know
you know related to the overall size of
the book which is 38 000 crore the new
flow will be much much smaller so you
don't see that impact too soon
while you see the impact of the market
market benefit of the bond book going
going away but anyways one book for us
more or less has been kind of more of an
atm strategy so we don't see a problem
with that
but as the mix of the book changes with
a greater flow coming in the increased
yield uh you know starts benefiting us
on the reinsurance allows google to
answer the question yeah i wish i happy
new to you as well uh i think on the
retention side knows as markov said
there is no specific change in the
retention philosophy that pretty much
kind of remains the same
is just that what you see in quarter one
typically you end up seeing a lot of
corporate renewals happening
where relatively the proportion of
reinsurance is higher and retention is
to that extent slightly lower
and whereas in quarter 2 i think if you
recollect what we have been saying a
consequent to the demerger we have also
kind of inherited the
crop book that barcelox had already kind
of committed to
and that book is something that got
booked in quarter two and which is why
you see a relatively lower retention for
quarter two
quarter three is typically the period
where you actually see a large part of
the business being underwritten on the
retail retail
franchise
predominantly motor and health where in
line with what we have mentioned no
change in the retention philosophy
typically these are small ticket
policies where our
retentions are relatively higher but
otherwise at an aggregate basis no
change in our retention velocity as such
it is purely a function of what kind of
bricks of business that we have
underwritten in q1 and q2
sure thanks thanks also quite clear uh
so basically one can then probably going
forward building that these kind of
thing the retention of the insurance
percentages would be broadly in line
with the mix of that particular quarter
uh just one thing if i can uh ask
on uh covet claims for the this quarter
if you can share the gopal that data how
was how were the net coverage claims for
us this quarter and
uh i believe that in last quarter we
mentioned that we could see some reserve
release also so what has been the
uh uh the trend there on kovit claims in
this quarter if you can just throw some
light on that
what we had talked about was for the
first half of the year
now that number if you look at on a nine
month basis stands revised at about 5.29
so hence to that extent while
in line with what we are seeing as let's
say declining trend on the wave two
related uh covet cases
obviously in uh relative to the approach
of reserving that we are kind of built
in in quarter one
as i said nine month number stands at
about 5.29 having said that i think what
it will be important for us to kind of
watch for which is what we will do in
quarter four is this uh
wave three impact that has started to
kind of play out obviously early trends
uh in terms of the number of
cashless intimations that we are seeing
tends to be slightly uh maybe lower than
the peak what we had seen in wave 2
but having said that obviously we will
monitor the development of intimations
because these are cashless requests
honestly we will have to wait for in
case if there are any reimbursement
claims that gets intimated which
typically happens at the lag
but on the wave 2 related uh kovit
impact i think as i said nine month
number stands at about 5.29
well that's
thank you
the next question is from the line of
nades jain from invested please go ahead
uh thanks for the opportunity
i said uh how should we think about
combined ratio and are we going forward
uh given that this was a pretty normal
quarter from uh uh from a claims ratio
perspective uh and our combined ratio is
around 105 for the quarter uh so uh how
should we think about combined ratio
over next coming year also we expect
some energy benefit to play out on the
operating cost uh so
uh
should we expect this number to turn
towards under present over here over
next couple of years
uh yeah
as you've been saying uh we believe that
i mean you know as you know the merger
just
the consolidation effectively happened
uh in the last month of last quarter so
we started taking uh most of the calls
that we need to take in terms of the
synergy benefit of the cost side
on the revenue side as i explained we've
uh we are quite happy with the way
things are playing out in terms of
the uh synergy with the existing
distribution that uh you know that that
bharti team had already built and we are
seeing growth coming through in some of
those partnerships as well
but the entire benefit for this as we've
been saying will take some time
uh and our sense is that we will start
to see the benefit play out maybe by you
know we have been saying fi 2024 but we
think it will probably be a bit uh
earlier than that so you know the second
down of next year we will start seeing
that benefit now if you look at the
combined uh you know on a pro forma
basis uh badgy pre uh
deal announcement and i said number
three digital announcement if you need a
pro forma integration
that would have been about 104 combined
uh so the question is how soon can we
bring that down now today what the
situation is that the
core underlying business of icc robot is
also not at uh you know the 500 number
that we used to experience because of
all the pressures that we've talked
about
so it may be you know challenging to
bring it under 100 that we have seen in
the past but directionally it will start
uh coming down and in terms of the
synergies uh
maybe gopal can explain some of the
things work that has already happened
yes
i think
i mean we have been we have been kind of
talking about broadly three areas of
synergy right i think in line with just
to kind of uh
refresh i think tax energies is
something that i mean as we fight we
will be filing the returns of 2021 by
january 31st so we will
in line with what we have said earlier
we will be able to absorb
the full benefit of the carry power
losses
on the cost spread i think as a part of
our operating remarks which is what we
kind of put out i think we have looked
at the
overall uh
office infrastructure and clearly i
think we have been able to kind of ah
keeping in mind the policy holder
interest we have been able to kind of
look at what kind of
existence do we need to have in so far
as physical offices are concerned and
clearly the numbers as at the 31st
december the number of office networks
stands revised at about 285
so again given the fact that this
rationalization of the office
infrastructure has happened in quarter
three and more towards
the latter part of the quarter so you
will again start to see some benefit of
the synergies in the form of cost
playing through from q4 onwards
equally i think we have been kind of
looking at various areas of uh
productivity improvements and
efficiencies which is what we are kind
of indicated on an earlier call to play
out over the next six to nine months so
there again we are on course
in order to be able to realize a better
improvement in productivity when we look
at the other cost elements the final
cost element in terms of technology
related spend where again we will be
able to kind of see benefits on synergy
playing out that will take some time
because over the next 9 to 12 months is
when we will be able to significantly
migrate
even let's say historical data and other
related information so the impact of
technology related spend on this synergy
front will start to play through most
probably towards the second half of the
next financial year but otherwise on
course to kind of realize most of the
cost elements that we are taught about
and the revenue synergies as bhargav
explained
is something that we will again start to
realize towards the second half of the
next financial period
sure
and secondly across
financial service segments we keep on
hearing noises around disruption
uh we have seen significant disruption
in some of the segments like broking and
in our industry also uh a lot of new age
companies are coming up
uh
in terms of distribution there is a
newest company coming up to the new age
model which are coming up in the
entire manufacturing side on the gender
insurance uh some of these business
models have also succeeded outside india
so how do we think about from a
long-term perspective uh with respect to
uh these uh possibility of disruption to
our business
so uh you know i think we've been
discussing this uh pretty regularly you
know if you look at the uh
the scope for disruption there are you
know both in terms of ensuring the way
people source policies they
people service policies very people
service claims
there is a tremendous scope for
disruption again using uh digital tools
that are
now available uh similarly there is also
some amount of disruption that is
possible in the
distribution side
now if you look at what we've been doing
is that on the on the first enter the
sourcing policies or servicing uh you
know policies through uh
uh you know modern day technology that's
been an area that we've been investing
heavily uh our
approach on the business side has been
as we you know mentioned in the opening
says
statement
uh focus was to create a carve out a
team which focuses on the digital
disruption on the
on the customer acquisition side
and we call it our digital one team
where we've kind of created a team which
is uh self-contained with you know all
key
capabilities you know and with separate
uh you know location separate
philosophies in terms of
even people you know processes and that
team has been ramping up and uh we are
reason we are quite happy with the way
the team is growing business both in
terms of
uh tying up with
digital uh ecosystem partners and as i
explained in this quarter we've seen a
70 growth in that
uh business as also in terms of the
business that gets written on our
website and we've seen about 20 growth
in this quarter on business written on
our website
now
the other thing that we have to study is
the uh
the uh you know honestly speaking the
fact that some of these players are
willing to uh lose a lot of money for
growth
uh we have to be a bit more calibrated
than some of them uh obviously our
philosophy has always been to
build a sustainable model
and we may not want to go to the level
of losses that some of them incurred but
even without that we are reasonably
confident that we are able to go we will
be able to go the segment quite fast
towards that we are also uh you know
you know towards this end of this
quarter we've taken a fair amount of
calls
and we believe that that will reflect an
even faster growth in this channel going
in
on the claims side
we've been giving out some numbers uh
you know in terms of digital claim
settlement that you've seen both from
motor and health using ai ml etc those
numbers are increasing by the quarter
even this quarter will have significant
increase in
the claims that we process through our
instaspect
service as also the
cashless authorization that we gave
using our ml feature
and similarly for us in terms of the
initiative on the ielts take care side
that's the way we believe we will be
able to engage uh with customers even
better uh on a web-based platform or our
mobile apps rather and
build a
greater connect while providing the
usual insurance services and there the
focus is not just in terms of the usual
things that you know insurance companies
provide but a lot more
uh
you know services and features
which increase
you know engagement and potentially
reduces risk for our customers
so this is a this is a big trust area
for us
in terms of digital disruption
sorry to interrupt request mr train to
please rejoin the queue we have
participants reading before return
thank you
the next question is from the lion of
sri shivani from clsa please go ahead
hi thank you thank you for the
opportunity hi sir i wanted to ask you a
question if i see the uh third quarter
uh uh gross numbers for uh lombard and
including
in the base so there has been a focus in
contraction for this quarter for the
combined entity while the industry or
the private players were at around five
to eight percent now motor we can see
has regrown much more twelve thirteen
percent for the combined entities while
the private players have still grown
around six percent on the health side
again uh lombard uh
consolidated book is around three
percent growth for third quarter while
uh the industry and the private players
are significantly higher so so if you
can uh if you can give us some
understanding of how do you plan what is
your growth uh target it's not target
but how do you plan uh your growth
across these two segments because these
are your largest segments basically and
what uh what should we expect for the
coming year or uh for the coming
quarters uh on on the growing side
yeah
let me take the two segments separately
uh let me start with motor
so
if you look at some of the commentary
that you've given on the motor side if
you look at the three sub-segments a
private car uh you know two-wheeler and
commercial vehicles
we are a bigger player in terms of the
private car sub segment and even a
bigger player when you look at the share
of new our share of new is much higher
than our normal share of
uh business as a company and at a time
when
the new sales have been muted for
reasons that all of us are aware largely
with chip shortage issues rather than
demand issue that has had a higher
impact on us than uh maybe the overall
industry
similarly if you look at our mix of
business two wheelers for us is a much
higher mix of business we have roughly
over 27 percent of our motor mix coming
from two wheelers industry mix would be
about roughly about 15
now two wheeler slow down has hence
affected us a bit more we you know from
a market share perspective we are fine
within the segment but from a mixed
perspective our
you know growth gets affected when two
wheelers goes down on the commercial
vehicle side there has been a growth
again you know while for the industry
commercial vehicle is roughly about 40
for us it's about 17 now so when that
segment grows faster than uh our sub is
then the other then relatively we
underperform having said that
there is also the pricing aggression
point that we've been making
and our sense is that most of the calls
that we wanted to take in terms of
correcting the portfolio has happened
and we remain uh
optimistic about growing or outgoing the
market from the coming quarters onward
on the motor segment on the health again
this is unfortunately a bit of a base
effect one because we were traditionally
more of a banker player and there was a
basis based effect in terms of uh
icc banks stopping to distribute uh
you know our benefit products that had
some amount of impact on our overall
business
uh but separate from that now we are
seeing that growth come back so as i
explain if you look at even during the
quarter uh you know while overall number
is your rightly identified that the
health business has
you know undergone for the quarter but
if you look at just the month of
december we've outgrown the market on
the health detail health indemnity bills
as we are adding more uh
agents and distribution that we've
talked about and similarly with the bank
that base effect is largely paid out
played out and our overall bank
distribution in in the month of december
has grown uh by about 15
because the base effect has got played
out and we are uh optimistic that this
will start uh going from this quarter
onwards even the bank has started
restarted uh he was selling uh not
benefit but our indemnity product as an
attachment just started so we'll have to
wait to see the impact it may say take a
bit of time
but overall uh i think the uh
base effect headwinds are behind us
and uh and on top of it we are investing
in terms of the retail agency
distribution that we've talked about so
all in all we are quite optimistic about
growth from
going going forward
and and uh also wanted to ask you uh
particularly on your health business uh
your group group business is a bigger
portion of your health portfolio so so
is there any target you're putting on
what kind of mix you want to maintain
between retail and group in the health
portfolio
we don't we take calls based on pure uh
you know risk selection i mean if let's
say
group health businesses uh
poorer we will cut down on google
business what we are very happy with is
what we've been saying for some time uh
from june onwards after the wave 2 we
went back to our corporate
clients for
price correction
you know obviously from from prospective
perspective not for the bank
uh and uh we said we will look at 50 to
20 price increase we are very happy to
say that for large corporates we've got
an even higher price increase on our
overall portfolio basis on a quarter
life premium
we factored in the potential uh you know
some potential third wave also in the
price and we are quite happy that we've
retained
more than 90 of our large corporate
accounts uh in spite of this kind of a
price increase so with this we are
reasonably confident about the group has
book book right now uh we'll have to
watch for the uh impact of covet wave 3
and the system pricing so we don't put a
target of mix we put a target of
profitability for each of the segments
sorry to interrupt me i request my
shreya to please rejoin the queue ma'am
yeah sure thank you thank you
ladies and gentlemen uh in order to
ensure that the management is able to
address questions from all participants
please limit your question to one per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
rahul from b capital p squared
happy new year to you uh my question is
uh you uh said that there were around
400 kind of uh
agents added
retail health side
but when i look at the numbers it is
some seventy from seventy eight thousand
it has gone to eighty two thousand
so this is uh how come only four hundred
in the rate retail
again
happy new year to you too
what the 400 number is our own sales
force that we hire on our rolls
the number that you are talking about is
the agent
count so what we do is you know these
people join uh our company and then they
recruit agents who are not on our own
these are commission agents side agents
or point-of-sale agents so
these are two different numbers now when
we get these 400 odd people as we
mentioned you know in the in the second
uh earnings conference call we wanted to
recruit about thousands or you want to
add about 1000 sales force in the in the
retail agency
channel these are people that will take
on roles each of them will then go out
and hire
agents to do the distribution
but for 400 of them have joined this
quarter then they will now go out and
you know hire more agents and they those
agents will then produce business on the
ground
thank you
the next question is from the line of
christian from otila please go ahead
yeah hi happy new year everyone uh
what was the health uh
a loss ratios uh in the quarter and uh
you know last previous quarter we had
some uh 67 curves of
uh
reserve release on the health book uh so
you know like to like comparison what
would have been the uh change ratio and
looking at the motor tp
where are we in the sense
talking about it or
what are the processes that are needed
for the price i can has anything been
started from
uh
yeah let me take the first part uh first
uh pressure uh on the on the first one
on the health loss ratios i think when
you when you look at the
investor tech we have put out the
numbers which includes health and
accident uh put together just on the
health side if you were to look at what
are two loss ratios for the overall
health book was 77.7
quarter three that number stands at
about 82.7
and if you look at quarter three
last year
uh which is for isis lombard on a
standalone basis the overall health loss
ratio stands at about 88.1
those are three numbers uh q2 77.7
q3 of current year 82.7
and q3 of last year il on a standalone
basis at 88.1 so those are three numbers
that's in response to the first question
appears
your second point on
the release of reserves that we had seen
in quarter two which is what i kind of
talked about
for the first half we had a net covered
impact of about 5.61 billion rupees
that's for the first half of the year
that number if you look at on a nine
month basis now stands revised at about
5.29 billion rupees
so hence to that extent i think uh
relative to the uh trend line what we
are seeing on account of wave 2 covet
cases i think the number stands devised
at about 5.29
as we as i mentioned i think obviously
what we will have to wait for is this
new wave three that has come through
what impact does it have both in terms
of count of intimation and two in terms
of average claim size i think as we move
forward in this quarter i think we will
be able to give share better insights
subsequently the initial trend seems to
suggest when we look at the cashless
count in terms of intimations on wave 3
relative to the peak that we had seen in
wave 2 the number of intimations under
wave 3 seems to be far lower so that's
one trend line but early early trends we
will have to wait as i said uh for more
data to come through
even on the claim size as we speak maybe
it looks like things the cases that are
getting intimidated are relatively
milder and hence to that extent maybe a
10 to 15 percent lower average killing
size than what we would have normally
seen in a
relative quarter that's what early
trends are obviously we have to wait for
for further intimation as and when we
get those intimidations so that's one
your second point on motor third party i
think we have been talking about the
price increase unfortunately we have not
seen a price change happening over the
last couple of years
having said that i think we have also
been talking about let's say increase in
in fact the average claim payouts
consequent to various court judgments
that we have seen over the last couple
of years
the expectation that we have is maybe as
we head into let's say maybe fi 23
hopefully we should be able to see some
form of a draft guideline getting put
out in terms of increasing motor third
party pricing
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sunken koda from spark capital please go
ahead
yeah thank you thank you for the
opportunity uh
we have seen a significant increase in
the optics on quarter on quarter basis
if you see the sales promotional
advertisement has increased almost
welcome eight percent q and q
um this is just one i wanted to
understand uh
why why it has gone up
given given it's a combined entity um we
thought this number will come down uh
compared to compared to what you have
done in second quarter and and and also
just wanted to understand this cost
therapy part itself
so so
if if there are low hanging source like
branch racialization and the employee
rationalization
then then what is the likely absolute
cost you could be saving during fi 23
and fi 24 so that your optics ratios uh
from from bharti axa ah
could could substantially improve in 23
and 24 compared to what we are seeing
right now around 35 percent is what we
have
30 is what we are seeing is right now
for the for the combining gtx of
commission
so maybe some case to your first
question on the sales promotion trend i
think maybe you have to always look at
the overall
expense ratios number in the context of
the mix of business that we have
i think as i kind of mentioned in one of
the responses to the earlier question q3
typically happens to the period where we
see typically bulk of the retail
business heating source
for example the mix of motor within
let's say whatever volumes of business
that you would have done in let's say q2
and q3 you will find
motor contribute contributing to a
relatively larger proportion of uh
gross return premiums and hence to that
extent correspondingly is where you will
get to see the cost of sourcing getting
uh
reflected in so far as excellent numbers
are concerned having said that i think
when you look at the aggregate
expense ratio numbers for quarter two
that number was at about 35.4 percent
this time talking about both operating
expenses plus commissions put together
for quarter two that number was about
35.4
that number is actually kind of slightly
uh come off
and that number stands at about thirty
four point nine percent so hence to that
extent we have actually seen
uh maybe a point five percent
improvement in the overall
uh management expense ratios uh in
quarter three compared to quarter two uh
so that so that's that's the
uh trend line that one would obviously
want to kind of uh
see as we kind of head into the
subsequent quarters uh if your point on
let's say some of the cost energy is
getting paid out which is what we
explained your point is absolutely right
all the office infrastructure space is
what i again responded to one of the
earlier questions if you look at
december 31 our office number stands
devised at about 285 as compared to
almost more than 400 plus offices which
we had towards the end of september so
we have clearly been able to kind of get
benefits of rationalization on the
office phase a large part of it happened
towards the second half of quarter three
and hence to that extent the impact in
the form of benefits on cost is
something that you will start to see it
playing through in the q4 number onwards
the same thing is what we would
obviously also want to see improvement
in efficiencies and productivity playing
out
even when it comes to on the people's
front again the impact of which is
something that we will see over the next
i would say six to 12 months kind of
time period the trajectory that one
would take is what i think vargo also
responded in so far as the combined
ratio is concerned again when you look
at quarter two combined we were at about
105.3
quarter three this uh numbers have come
to 104.5
and over the period i think you would
obviously want to try and see if you can
start seeing improvement in combined as
we head into this uh subsequent quarters
that's how the cost energies would play
out every cost element is being looked
at and some of the
immediate benefits is something that we
already started to see and certain
elements of cost particularly assisted
on the technology side will play through
towards the second half of fy23
thank you
ladies and gentlemen you are requested
to please limit your question to one per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
avena singh from mk global peace corps
[Music]
hi good evening uh
two questions one firstly on that you
know your retail health clearance ratio
seems to be higher size if you three
despite some 30 odd crore of uh you know
kobe reserve religious
uh adjustment so was it sort of uh in
certifying due to increasing frequency
of non-covered or delayed procedures or
was there some sort of a change on the
you know
severity side so that's on the detail
health part
and secondly uh on the motor side uh now
we have talked a lot about competition
what uh and one was told that okay or
rarely it has happened that two three
years of intense competition but one
thing that's different in this time of
competition
is that there are a lot of new players
like uh they have been funded or being
funded on the patterns of you know the
futuristic uh
insure tech business where sort of uh
you know the justice period or
willingness to take losses is pretty
high for longer period and on the other
hand you have that the you know that the
large incumbents struggling to just
maintain their top line of course they
have been uh recapitalized so their
ability again to drag you know the
pricing is better or i mean at least
higher this side so these are two
questions so how do you see that comp i
mean motor only competition easing out
well we asked great questions uh on the
first one uh
it was largely because uh elevated
frequency of non-copic claims that we
see
we've been talking about it and in q3 we
had both medical acute cases which is
basically the dengue malaria cases which
kind of
you know kind of continued from q2
usually it's linked to the monsoon
season it's continued in the early part
of q3
and separately on top of that the
elective surgery numbers have been
quite high for q3
thirdly signs in q4 both those you know
medical acute cases came down in the
second half of q3 and even electric
surgeries right now is again trending
down but we'll have to watch this trend
for uh for a period in terms of acs very
similar to the number that we give in
the last earnings call over a two year
period we've seen roughly about twenty
percent increase so about nine to ten
percent uh annualized increase in
average game size is what we are seeing
uh which is largely a medical inflation
that we are seeing uh we will have to
again wait to see if this is structural
we explain the reason why we think this
is happening in terms of
uh additional tests upp suits etc uh but
you know till covet plays through this
will remain and then you know and
thereafter we'll have to wait to see if
this is structured so that's on the
health side
on the motor side you know your point is
absolutely valid uh in the past we've
not seen a
kind of a pe-funded entity which is just
going for growth
we've had disciplined
you know insurers who've come into the
market
so that risk is there having said that
we uh
we believe that um
from our perspective we've taken the
necessary calls that we wanted to uh
this year and we are reasonably
confident that on this base will
continue to grow on the motor book
i'm hoping that there will be some price
correction next year because of tp etc
but even otherwise we've kind of geared
up to handle the sector
we've done a lot of granular analysis
during this year to prepare ourselves
for a situation where
you know this market continues to remain
aggressive
and we will still be able to compete
with ourselves
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sakash kapadia from moneygate portfolio
managers please go ahead
yeah but thanks for the opportunity
now bhargava you mentioned about you
know the app downloads 1.1 million so
you know are we happy with this number
and can you share some customer
experiences because you know
the app has certain very good features
like a consultation or a diet planning
so you know how is the customer
experience been because you know some of
these things once you know
they are appreciated and kick in
automatically you know stickiness and
cross-sell can improve for us and you
know dental insurance there was some tie
up so is it you know under the same
policy are you know some of these uh
initiatives for creating a more
differentiation at our retail level kind
of focus which is absolutely absolutely
correct you know this is exactly our
thought process on the on the benefit of
the app from a longer term perspective
if you look at the number 1.1 billion is
just scratching the surface
we launched this app
about two years back
largely focused on the
business to employ segment which is
basically the group health segment for
uh you know employees of our corporates
at that point in time our thought
process was this was a segment where
with whom we had hardly any engagement
uh
in in corporates wouldn't even realize
that the insurance was from uh isis but
unless they had a claim
and you know a small percentage of
people actually claimed so the whole
thought process was to build engagement
and then very rapidly we realized that
we needed to pivot and provide uh you
know a comprehensive uh you know
solution across product lines to these
uh uh to these customers because the
same customer was an employee of a
corporate is also a retail uh you know
insurance customer of ours
through maybe a motor or some other
policy
so we've been consistently pivoting and
you know or we've pivoted and we've been
consistently
building features on agile mode every 15
days we launched new new features on
that app and the number of downloads
that we are seeing is really a two-year
story right now we are adding almost
hundred thousand uh you know new uh app
users uh every month
on the service and the engagement we are
watching it like a hawk uh there is uh
you know we believe
you're absolutely right we believe this
will create stickiness and improve
process
we launched uh the renewal and the
crosstal uh you know upsell module uh in
the middle of this year uh around june
or july or august if i recollect and
month on month we are seeing good
traction in terms of uh people using the
app for
uh upselling or cross cross selling but
on a very small way so numbers are not
meaningful in the overall scheme of
things but the growth numbers are
quite phenomenal
we'll wait for some time before the
numbers become meaningful to talk about
some of these is my guess but overall we
are very clear that this is going to be
a
tool to you know build a strong
engagement with our customers which will
in the long term help us with
across the lap cell you know and we
believe even loss ratio
thank you
ladies and gentlemen this was the last
question for today i would now like to
hand the conference over to mr
bhargavdas gupta for closing comments
thank you
you know again thank you everyone for
joining this call you know we are
available for
answering any other call separately feel
free to reach out in case you had a
question then time didn't permit us to
answer those then
and look forward to engaging you during
the quarter and thereafter thank you and
take care bye thank you so much thank
you
thank you
on behalf of ica lombard general
insurance that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines